So we have two ways of looking at math, we have
the computational world of syntax, and the platonic world of semantics.
To understand the relation between these two worlds, let's start with
a simple language with a single binary relation symbol E.
We can visualize models in this language by
sets of points and arrows between these points.
We need to define axioms to determine
the behaviour of this edge relation E.
Without any axioms, every possible combination of points and all possible
arrows drawn between them is a model of our empty theory.
An axiom can be any FOL sentence.
For example, we can consider
this formula phi, expressing transitivity,
meaning that if there is some path between nodes,
then there is a direct path between these nodes,
or this sentence psi expressing irreflexitivity, which enforces that any
model of it must not contain any self-referential arrows.
Such sentences are true in some of
the structures, and false in others.
We can combine the sentences, and consider the collection of
all structures which satisfy both phi and psi for example,
i.e. the collection of all transitive and irreflexive structures.
We will denote this collection by the model set of phi and psi.
If we start to analyze the structures in this collection, we
might notice some things in common to all of them.
For example we may notice that in none of them do we
have an arrow from a to b and from b to a.
We can easily see why, since if we did have an edge from a
to b and from b to a in a transitive and irreflexive structure,
then by transitivity we should have a direct path a to a.
But then the structures is not irreflexive, a contradiction.
So, we see that adding this
sentence chi expressing assymetry, is redundant,
in the sense that Mod(phi,psi,chi)=Mod(phi,psi).
We denote this by  models chi.